cessna.com 2018-11-24

# Privacy Policy

## General

At Textron Aviation Inc. (“TAI”) we know you care about your personal privacy. Because we care too, we have adopted the practices described in this Privacy Policy. You should not access this website (the “Site”), purchase products or use our services until you have carefully read this Privacy Policy and agree to the terms and conditions described in it.

Certain areas of the Site or associated websites or webpages dealing with TAI products or services may contain their own privacy policy because of the services provided or transactions conducted through those specific areas. You should not access those areas, use the services of or conduct transactions in those areas until you have carefully read the associated private policy and agree to the terms and conditions. If there is any inconsistency between this Privacy Policy and an area specific privacy policy, the area specific privacy policy controls.

## OUR COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We collect and use information about you which will help us administer our business or provide products, services or other opportunities to you. Among other things, we use the information we learn about you to help us personalize and improve the experience you have on our website, to respond to your requests and to communicate with you.

## Personal Data We Collect

The types of information we collect, retain and use include the following:

1\. Site Use Information

In general, you can visit the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. Our web servers collect the domain names, not the email addresses, of visitors.

2\. Registration Information You Provide to Us

Personally Identifiable Information and Voluntarily Provided Additional Information

Generally, you are not required to register in order to access our Site. However, when you send us an email, contact us to provide or receive information or news, receive products or services or register in connection with a specific area of the Site, we collect profile information from you ("Personally Identifiable Information”). When you register, we require that you provide the following Personally Identifiable Information:

  * Your first and last name;
  * Email address; and
  * Other information as requested in the applicable registration pages.

At your option, you may voluntarily provide additional information (including employment history if you are seeking employment at TAI). Although you may choose not to provide the optional information to us, it may result in some features not being available to you.

## How Long We Keep Your Information

The personal data that is collected by us will only be retained as long as necessary for business continuity or valid legal purposes.

## How We Use the Information We Collect

1\. Site Use Information

This information may be aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the Site, pages viewed, the site you visited just before coming to this Site, internet service provider, etc. This information ("Behavior Profiles") is used to measure the use of our Site and to improve the content we offer.

2\. Personally Identifiable Information

By providing Personally Identifiable Information to us, you explicitly agree to our collection and use of such information as described in this Privacy Policy. We use your Personally Identifiable Information in the following ways:

  * To respond to your inquiries;
  * To process an order or request;
  * To contact you regarding account status or customer service;
  * To ask you for feedback on our service;
  * To let you know about products or services which may be of interest to you;
  * To allow you to access specific account information; or
  * To match you with appropriate job opportunities if you are seeking employment at TAI.

When you register, order products or services or provide information through this Site, you consent to allow us to contact you for these purposes.

We may store the information you share with us for marketing research and other marketing purposes. You consent to our making your email addresses available to other reputable organizations associated with TAI whose products or services we think you may find interesting.

If you do not want to receive information about our products and services, you will be provided with the opportunity to easily opt-out of participation or you may contact [WebMaster@txtav.com](mailto:WebMaster@txtav.com).

Be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personal information in public areas of the Site, such as chat rooms or bulletin boards, this information may be seen and used by others. So be sure to exercise good judgment when sharing personal information in these forums.

3\. Email Communications

We use your email address to contact you to respond to your inquiries or to provide information on products or services to you. To help us determine whether you have received an email from us and to help us make emails more useful and interesting, we may receive a confirmation that you have opened an email from us.

4\. Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information that a website can store on your web browser and then retrieve at a later time. We may use cookies to enable us to remember your password, track the portions of the Site you visit, help us identify the portions of our Site that may be the most relevant for your needs, and to help us identify other products or services that may be of interest to you or others. While we use cookies to track the portions of our Site you visit, we do not use cookies to examine your surfing behavior before or after you leave our Site. There are products commercially available that are designed to help you disable cookies. Although we want you to be aware that such products exist, please note that if you choose to use them we will not be able to provide you with personalized service, and it may result in certain features and services not being available to you.

## CHILD PRIVACY

Because of the nature of our business, our products and services are not designed to appeal to minors, and therefore we do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive any information from children. Our terms and conditions of use require that any registration may only be made by those age 18 or older and that any product or service purchases may only be made by those age 18 or older. If we have reason to believe that information is being provided by a child under the age of 18, TAI will not collect the information without parental consent or parent notification, which will include the opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information or to prevent the child's participation in the activity. Without parental consent, online information will only be used to respond to an unsolicited request and for no other purpose. We recognize that protecting children's identities and privacy online is important and that the responsibility to do so rests with both the online industry and with parents.

## RESTRICTIONS ON DISCLOSING INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES

We do not sell or lease your Personally Identifiable Information to others, but we may share your Personally Identifiable Information with our affiliated companies or authorized representatives and you agree to allow us to do so.

1\. Site Use Information

We may share experiential information or other data which does not personally identify users of our Site with third parties. For example, this might include product or service preferences of all visitors to our Site.

2\. Personally Identifiable Information

We do not reveal Personally Identifiable Information about you to unaffiliated third parties, unless: 

  * you request or authorize it;
  * the information is provided to help complete a transaction for you;
  * the information is provided to comply with the law, applicable regulations, court orders or subpoenas, to enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements, or to protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of our users or others (e.g., to a consumer reporting agency for fraud protection, etc.);
  * the disclosure is done as part of a purchase, transfer or sale of services or assets (e.g., in the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by another party, customer information may be one of the transferred assets); or
  * the information is provided to our agents, outside vendors or service providers to perform functions on our behalf (e.g., analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing customer service, etc.).

We may also gather aggregated data about you and disclose such aggregated (but not personally identifiable) information to third parties for promotional or other purposes.

EU Personal Data will only be transferred to third parties outside of the EU if:

  * the third-party data controller processes the personal data in accordance with a Commission decision finding that a third- party country provides adequate protection; or
  * the third-party data controller becomes a signatory to Model Clauses with Textron Inc. or an affiliate or another data transfer agreement approved by a competent authority in the EU; or
  * data subjects have been given the opportunity to object, after having been informed of the purposes of the transfer, the categories of recipients and the fact that the countries to which data is exported may have different data protection standards.

## SECURITY PROCEDURES TO PROTECT INFORMATION

We maintain security standards and procedures to help prevent unauthorized access to confidential information about you. Our Site uses a combination of encryption technology and authentication to protect your Personally Identifiable Information. As long as the web browser you are using supports Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), your information will be submitted to us with a high level of security. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis. We have procedures limiting employee access to Personally Identifiable Information to those employees who have a business reason to know such information about you.

It is important for you to help protect against unauthorized access by signing off of our Site each time you finish using the Site.

## INAPPLICABILITY OF PRIVACY POLICIES OF ANY LINKED SITES OR OTHER PARTIES

This Site may contain links to other sites such as affiliates, subsidiaries or other third-party distributors and sales representatives. This Privacy Policy only addresses TAI’s use and disclosure of your Personally Identifiable Information collected on this Site. While we try to link only to sites that share our standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third parties or the content of linked sites, and we encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies and terms and conditions of such parties or websites. TAI has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or sites.

## YOUR RIGHTS TO THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

This Privacy Policy is intended to provide you with information about what personal data TAI collects about you and how it is used. If you have any questions, please contact TAI’s privacy lead at [MMTopping@txtav.com](mailto:MMTopping@txtav.com) or [LDHarms@txtav.com](mailto:LDHarms@txtav.com). 

If you wish to confirm that TAI is processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal data that TAI may have about you, please contact TAI’s privacy lead at: [MMTopping@txtav.com](mailto:MMTopping@txtav.com) or [LDHarms@txtav.com](mailto:LDHarms@txtav.com).

You may also request information about the purpose of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned, what the source of the information was (if you didn’t provide it directly to TAI) and how long it will be stored. You have a right to correct (rectify) the record of your personal data maintained by TAI if it is inaccurate. You may request that TAI erase that data or cease processing it, subject to certain exceptions. You may also request that TAI cease using your data for direct marketing purposes. When technically feasible, TAI will—at your request—provide your personal data to you or transmit it directly to another controller.

Reasonable access to your personal data will be provided at no cost upon request made to TAI’s privacy lead at: [MMTopping@txtav.com](mailto:MMTopping@txtav.com) or [LDHarms@txtav.com](mailto:LDHarms@txtav.com).

If access cannot be provided within a reasonable time frame, TAI will provide you with a date when the information will be provided. If for some reason access is denied, TAI will provide an explanation as to why access has been denied.

## TERMS OF USE, NOTICES AND CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

In the event of any conflict between the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, then the Terms of Use shall control.

As our business changes, this Privacy Policy, area specific private policies, the Terms of Use and additional terms and conditions applicable to specific areas (collectively “Policies and Terms”) are expected to change from time to time, and we reserve the right to change the Policies and Terms at any time. The use of your information is subject to the Policies and Terms in effect at the time of use. The provisions contained herein supersede all previous notices or statements regarding our privacy practices with respect to this Site. We may email periodic reminders of our policies and terms and conditions and post any changes to the Policies and Terms on our Site. We encourage you to check our Site frequently to see the current Policies and Terms and if changes that may have been made to them.

## HOW TO CONTACT US WITH QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY

To contact us regarding any questions about this Privacy Policy or to register a complaint with TAI or a data protection authority, please contact TAI’s privacy lead at: [MMTopping@txtav.com](mailto:MMTopping@txtav.com) or [LDHarms@txtav.com](mailto:LDHarms@txtav.com).
